Okay guys welcome to another video, so in this video we'll be seeing another one method,
the last and final method, Windows service, so let me show you how to do that, so this
is the command, we can add a service, so creating the name of the persistent process service
and the binary path will be our post-system.exe and start output when we move to our machine,
so this will be automatically, let's start out okay, so let me execute this command in
my Windows machine, so here you can see the creating a service, the service is created
successfully and let me query the service, so don't worry, I'll be giving each and every
command in our resource session, you can find that, so here you can see the new service
get added, post-system is, and let me restart my machine, so to verify that as being successfully
added, okay, successfully executing, so before that I'll be start my listener here and
now I'll be restarting my machine, so let wait for a few minutes, now my machine has been
started, let me give a username password, so let me open this, see how fast it was, so I
got a connection, so let me check a privilege from here, so here you can find it's a system
mandatory level, so when you adding any task in a service, okay, so let's exclude the
schedule task, when you adding any executable under the service, so that will be running
a system mandatory level, okay, so you have to be a bit aware about that, okay, we have
successfully completed the persistence mechanism, the five persistent mechanism, and we'll
be, we'll move on to the detection method, so how we can detect the schedule task and
the service of that has been created, so that was very simple to investigate, both the
things, just go to the log folder, see windows, system 32, VIN EVT logs, so for investigating
the schedule task, you need to find the security, security-based logs, let's open that
and filter it with the 4, 6, 9, 8, even tidy, okay, that was the schedule task creation
even tidy, so 4, 6, 9, 8, so here you can find the data was today, 3, 5, 20, 25, and
9, 0, 6, we have recorded about a previous video in the 9, 0, 6, I feel, here you can find
the task, so the command had been executed that has been here, so you need to investigate
the 4, 6, 9, 8, so let me check the 4, 6, 9, 9, so that was a schedule task deletion
even, so here you can see the task name has been deleted, so the schedule task has been
deleted, so this is how you can investigate the schedule task creation, for investigating
the service, so you need to check the system logs, the even tidy was 0, 4, 5, let's
give some time, let's get started, let me filter the 7, 0, 4, 5, so here you can find
there is a new work, a service was installed in the machine, at the date of today, 3, 5,
20, 25, the service path will be the C user download for systemL.exe, and the user
mode, service and auto-start, service account is a local system, so here you can find
the information, so for a schedule task we will be going to investigate 4, 6, 9, 8, and
4, 6, 9, 9, but service you are going to investigate the 7, 0, 4, 5, 1 tidy, so for schedule
task you need to investigate the security even logs, for services you will be investigating
the system even logs, so that's the small difference, both those things, yep, that's all
about the persistence mechanism, 5 persistence mechanism in Windows, so I hope you have
a clear understanding, all the 5 things, you have seen everything in a practical way,
let me remove this task in the same way, RLC will be creating it again and again, let
me do that quick, so the instant response is like how will be deleting the schedule task,
how will be deleting the registries, how will be relating the service, this is the same
way you are going to do, when you are dealing with the instant response, if you need to
remove some task or if you need to remove some services or anything, the same way nothing
will be going to change, yeah, I feel everything looks good, we will hope I will continue
our discussion in the next video of the account creation, bye bye.